## Samuel Jackson

CONTACT Information 54 Rhosendre, Waun Fawr, Aberystwyth, SY23 3PU *Tel:* 07895 318714 *E-mail:* slj11@aber.ac.uk

Twitter: @sljack92 Website: samueljackson.me

Profile

I am a fourth year undergraduate software engineering student at Aberystwyth university. I have already completed two years of my undergraduate with an average of a first. I have also recently finished an industrial placement year as a software engineer at the Science and Technology Facilities Council. In this role worked as part of an international development team to build a cutting edge data analysis application. I am now six months into the fourth year of my degree and have just started working on my dissertation project involving mammogram image analysis.

KEY SKILLS

**Communication**: During my industrial placement I worked daily with customers who were technical experts in their field to realise their computing needs. As a practical demonstrator it was important to communicate technical content clearly with people who are less knowledgeable than myself. My experience as a student ambassador and staff-student committee member taught me to communicate ideas and opinion effectively to both staff and students.

**Teamwork**: I've recently worked as part of a international, multi-skilled development team as part of my industrial placement. During my time I worked on many different projects involving different subsets of the team each with different skills and domain knowledge meet the project's goals. I completed a major group project as part of my degree which simulated a real world project where I took on the role of lead developer. I was successfully able to orchestrate the team to build a work end product.

**Planning and Organisation:** On my placement year I was responsible for collaborating with customers on the design and implementation of an entire section of the project. I also responsible for redesigning one of the core features of the system, from requirements analysis through to implementation.

**Technical Knowledge:** IY project was primarily written in C++ and my university's group project module was a Java web application using a MySQL database. During this year I create a RESTful client application from scratch for an internet applications assignment.

EDUCATION

# University of Aberystwyth

Ceredigion, Wales, UK

September 2011 - Present

MEng. Software Engineering, September 2011 (expected graduation date: June 2016)

### Key Modules:

- C, C++ and Java Programming (86%)
- Program Design, Data Structures and Algorithms (88%)
- Modelling Persistent Data (96%)
- Web Development Tools (94%)
- Developing Internet Based Applications (Result Pending)

## **New College**

Swindon, Wiltshire, UK

September 2008 - June 2011

- BTEC National Diploma in Software Engineering: Triple Distinction
- Business Studies A Level: B
- Computing AS Level: B
- Biology AS Level: B

**Dorcan Technology Collage**, Swindon, Wiltshire, UK

September 2003 - June 2008

10 GCSE's grades A\*-C including Maths grade A and English grade A.

## Professional Experience

### Software Developer, STFC

Rutherford Appleton Laboratory, Harwell, Oxfordshire, UK

July, 2013 - August, 2014

I have recently been employed as a software developer for ISIS Neutron source based at Rutherford Appleton Laboratory in Harwell, Oxfordshire to develop the Mantid neutron and muon data analysis application. This project was primarily written in C++ and Python. I was primarily responsible for the development of the framework for indirect geometry instruments, but also helped develop the general framework during my time with the project. I was involved with every step of the development process from requirements gathering to design, through to implementation, testing, and maintenance. My original contract was extended so I could continue working through the summer before university began.

### Practical Demonstrator, University of Aberystwyth

Aberystwyth, Ceredigion, Wales, UK

October, 2012 - June, 2013, September 2014 - Present

I am currently employed as a practical demonstrator for Aberystwyth University helping to teach Java, C++, C and Haskell. This position sharpens my communication and technical skills as I must be able to confidently pass on my knowledge to others and explain complicated concepts clearly.

Honors and Awards Glyn Emery prize for best first year student, University of Aberystwyth, 2012.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE AND SKILLS • Languages: Java, JavaScript, PHP, C++, Python, C, Haskell.

• Applications: Eclipse, Qt Designer.

• Tools: Git, CMake, GDB, Valgrind, LATEX.

• Libraries: Boost, Numpy, Scipy, scikit-learn, scikit-image, CxxTest, JUnit, Qt, JQuery.

• Operating Systems: Unix/Linux, Mac OSX, and Windows.

### Volunteering

### **Student-Staff Consultative Committee Member**

University of Aberystwyth, Aberystwyth, Ceredigion, UK

September 2014 - Present

Since my return to Aberystwyth I have volunteered to be a member of the staff-student consultative committee. This position has involved attending and contributing to regular committee meetings and aiding with student drop in sessions.

### Student Ambassador

University of Aberystwyth, Aberystwyth, Ceredigion, UK

August 2012 - Present

I am currently volunteering to be an open day and visit day ambassador for the university. The role requires me to talk to prospective students and their families about what it is like to live and study in Aberystwyth. I am also responsible for giving tours of the computer science department and helping to get prospective students to talks and interviews conducted by the department on time.

Interests

In my free time I enjoy reading (mostly classics and science fiction) and playing tennis and squash. During my industrial year I got involved with the department's Aunt Sally team where we won the cup.

References

Prof. Reyer Zwiggelaar, rrz@aber.ac.uk

Director of Research, IMPACS, University of Aberystwyth, Aberystwyth, Ceredigion, UK

Mr. Nick Draper, nick.draper@stfc.ac.uk

Mantid Project Manager, Rutherford Appleton Laboratory, Harwell, Oxfordshire, UK